Portfolio GitHub in LinkedIn

82 Plymouth Avenue, Maplewood, NJ 07040 • mark@markreilly.com • 347 228 3696

## Summary

I am a User Experience Designer with over eighteen years in interactive media. My career spans the breadth of digital production, from production art to web design and front-end development. As a User Experience Designer, my in-depth understanding of the design process allows me to meet user goals while balancing aesthetics and technical constraints.

### **UX/UI Skills**

- · Usability Testing, User Interviews, and Personas
- · Sketching, Storyboarding, and Paper Prototyping
- · Wireframing, Card Sorting, and High-fidelity Prototyping
- · Markup (HTML) and Styling (CSS)
- · Visual Design, Style Guides, and Style Tiles
- · Typography and Graphic Production

#### Technical Skills

- Sketch, Photoshop, OmniGraffle, Illustrator, Principle, Flash
- HTML, CSS, Sass & Compass, Javascript & jQuery, Grunt & Gulp
- · Git & SVN, PHP, MySQL, Drupal

# **Professional Experience**

## KBS (kirshenbaum bond senecal)

March 2015-present

#### **Associate Director, User Experience**

KBS (kirshenbaum bond senecal) November 2016–present

- Create a design system, user flows, and a prototype for Stanley Black & Decker's Lista product configurator
- Design a skills matrix for the UX team to visualize strengths and gaps within the team. The skills matrix helps with allocations, skills training, and career development.
- Create a Sketch and InVision based workflow to streamline work between departments; Wireframes are created by UX designers, visualized by UI designers, and then prepared for handoff to developers

#### Senior User Experience Designer

Spies & Assassins | KBS (kirshenbaum bond senecal) March 2015–November 2015

- Create a modular design system, wireframes, user flows, and prototypes for the responsive redesign of the BMW USA website
- Create wireframes, user flows, and prototypes for the redesign of the My BMW website
- Conduct user interviews and create content types and wireframes for the Hershey's digital marketing learning site

## New York University

October 2008-March 2015

#### **User Experience Specialist**

Digital Communications Group, Information Technology Services August 2014–March 2015

- Create a new responsive user interface for Sakai, an Open Source Learning Management System
- · Commit back the user experience work from NYU Classes to Sakai
- Design a new user interface for NYU's *Email Direct* a bulk email communication tool for NYU administrators

#### **User Experience Designer**

Academic Technology Services, Information Technology Services October 2011-August 2014

- Design a new user interface for NYU Classes the Learning Management System (LMS) based on extensive usability testing
- Create a 'Mobile First' prototype for our redesign of MediaCommons a digital network for professors and post-graduate students of film and media studies

#### **Interactive Designer and Developer**

Faculty Technology Services, Information Technology Services October 2008-October 2011

- Design and develop MediaCommons a digital network for professors and post-graduate students — using Drupal
- · Establish a distinctive look and feel for the MediaCommons network and it's project sites
- Design and develop book and photo viewing websites, and streaming audio and video for the NYU Libraries' special digital collections

# Columbia University August 2001-September 2008

#### Senior Web Designer and Developer

Columbia University Digital Knowledge Ventures (a small 'digital agency' within Columbia University)

May 2005-September 2008

- · Create educational course content and departmental websites for Columbia University and affiliated non-profits
- · Design and develop websites using open source content management systems and static html

#### Web Designer and Developer

Columbia University Digital Knowledge Ventures August 2001-May 2005

- · Work with Columbia Faculty to design and develop interactive e-seminars and courses
- Design and develop interactive maps, audio slideshows, podcasts, and basic video production and post-production for streaming video and DVD

#### Scholastic

January 2000-May 2001

#### **Web Designer**

e-Scholastic

- · Design educational, commercial, and promotional websites for Scholastic
- · Design daily site graphics, flash based interactive quizzes and educational activities

## Education

1999-2007 Ph.D. Media & Communication, European Graduate School, Saas-Fee, Switzerland

1998-2001 Certificate in Film Production, The New School, New York, NY

1995–1996 M.Phil. Medieval History, Trinity College, Dublin University, Ireland

1991-1994 B.A. History and Philosophy, University College Dublin, Ireland